리프 카페
Unbelievable!
It's been half an hour.
30분 째 메뉴판만
보고 있잖아
이게 만화라면
네가 햄으로 보일 거야
If this was a cartoon,
you'd look like a ham now.
웨이트리스 저기 있네
여기요!
-There's the waitress. Hello, miss!
-It's Phoebe!
피비 아냐!
- 안녕
- 안녕?
-Okay, will that be all?
-Wait. What are you doing here?
이제 됐나요?
여기서 뭐 하는 거야?
I was over there. Then you said,
"Hello, miss." So I'm here.
저기 있는데 이 사람이
부르길래 왔죠
No, how come you're working here?
왜 여기서 일하냐고?
집에서도 가깝고
앞치마도 예쁘거든요
Because it's close to where I live,
and the aprons are cute.
-Can we start over?
-Okay, I'm gonna be over here.
차근차근 짚어볼까?
- 그럼 다시 가 있을게요
- 안돼!
The One With Two Parts - Part l
그 녀석이 날 시험해보려는
건지도 모르지만
I don't know whether
he's testing me...
원숭이가 말썽만 피워
... but my monkey is out of control!
응답기 메시지를
계속 지우는 거야
He keeps erasing
the messages on my machine.
뭐 실수였겠지만
Supposedly by accident.
나도 많이 해봤지
Oh, yeah, I've done that.
And then he got to
the newspaper before I did...
보지도 않은 신문에
3일 연짱 오줌을 갈겼어
...and peed all over the crossword!
I've never done that.
그건 안 해봤는데
Last night, I don't know what he did
but there were capers everywhere!
어젯밤엔 뭘 했는지
사방에 케이퍼 천지더라구
-She looks exactly like her sister.
-I'm saying I see a difference.
봐! 완전 붕어빵인데
뭐가 아니야?
내 눈엔 달라 보여
They're twins.
쌍둥이라구
그래도 피비하곤 달라
우르술라는 화끈하다구
I don't care.
Phoebe's Phoebe. Ursula's hot!
우리 그 동안
척척 통했었잖아?
You know how we talk about things?
- 응
- 이젠 아니야
-Let's not do that anymore.
-All right.
- 왔어?
- 안녕?
피비, 오늘 누구 만났게?
-Pheebs, guess who we saw today?
-Oh, fun! Okay.
와! 재밌겠다
- 리암 니슨
- 아니
-Liam Neeson.
-No.
- 몰리 세이퍼
- 땡!
-Morley Safer.
-No.
- 내 머리 자른 미용사!
- 아냐
-The lady who cuts my hair!
-This could be a very long game.
이러다 날새겠다
-Your sister, Ursula.
-Oh, really?
- 네 언니 우르술라
- 그래?
- 길 건너 카페에서 일하던데
- '리프' 말이지?
-She works at that place....
-Riff's. I know.
알아? 둘이 몇 년째
말도 안 한다던데?
You do? She said you guys
haven't talked in years.
맞아
뚱뚱하디?
So, is she fat?
쭉쭉빵빵이던걸
Not from where I was standing.
Where were you standing?
네가 보기엔?
Pheebs, so you guys
just don't get along?
피비, 사이가
안 좋은 거야?
자매끼리 왜
그런 거 있잖아
It's mostly just dumb sister stuff.
다들 언니가 나보다
예쁘다는 거 있지?
Everyone always thought of her
as the pretty one.
걸음마도 먼저 시작했어
난 좀 늦었지
She was the first to walk even
though I did it later that same day.
몇 시간 뒤였으니까
부모님한테 걸음마는
이미 시시한 거였거든
But to my parents, by then it was,
"Yeah, what else is new?"
I'm sorry. I've gotta go.
I've got Lamaze class.
미안한데 먼저 일어날게
라마즈 수업이 있어
난 지구과학 듣는데
체육관에서 봐
And I've got earth science,
but I'll catch you in gym?
-ls this just gonna be you and Carol?
-Susan will be there too.
캐롤하고 둘이 가?
아니, 수잔도 있어
아빠 둘에 레즈비언 둘이니
We've got dads, we've got lesbians.
The whole parenting team.
막강 부모군단이지
좀 그렇지 않아?
-lsn't that gonna be weird?
-lt might have been at first...
아니, 처음에야 그랬지만
이젠 정말 아무렇지도 않아
... but now I'm comfortable with it.
- 오빠, 내 옷이야
- 알아
-Ross, that's my jacket.
-I know.
안녕하세요?
로스튼 부부예요
Hi. We're the Rostens.
I'm J. C. and he's Michael.
전 JC이고
이 이는 마이클이죠
저흰 아들하고
딸을 가졌어요
And we're having a boy and a girl.
축하드려요
자, 다음?
Good for you.
All right, next?
전... 로스 겔러이고
제 아들이 여기 있어요
I'm Ross Geller.
And that's my boy in there.
이쪽은 캐롤 윌릭,
이쪽은 수잔 번치인데
And this is Carol Willick.
And this is Susan Bunch.
Susan is Carol's....
수잔은 캐롤의...
다음!
Who's next?
Sorry, Susan is...?
- 죄송하지만 뭐라구요?
- 캐롤의 친구라구요
-Carol's friend.
-Life partner.
- 인생의 동반자죠
- 우정이 대단해요
Like buddies.
서로 사랑하죠
-Like lovers.
-You know how close women can get.
여자들의 찐한 우정 아시죠?
- 우린 같이 살아요
- 결혼은 저랑 했었죠
-We live together.
-I was married to her.
- 저 말고 캐롤이랑요
- 네
-Carol, not me.
-It's a bit complicated.
- 좀 복잡해요
- 약간은
- 이젠 잘 지내요
- 당연한 말씀!
-But we're fine.
-Absolutely!
So, twins!
That's like two births.
쌍둥이면...
일석이조네요
이런!
Ouch!
나도 '부르르릉'
뭐야, 헬렌?
to you too, Helen.
-Nina Bookbinder is here to see you.
-Okay, send her in.
니나 부크바인더가 왔어요
들여보내
- 안녕하세요?
- 니나! 어서 와
-Come on in.
-You wanted to see me?
- 부르셨다구요?
- 그래
I was reviewing your data. You've
been postdating your Friday numbers.
살펴봤는데 금요일 자료의
날짜를 틀리게 적었더군
-Which is bad, because...?
-lt throws my WENUS out of whack.
그건요...
그것 땜에 거시기가
엉망이 됐다구
-Excuse me?
-WENUS.
뭐라구요?
- 주간 전산망사용통계 말야
- 전산망 사용 통계요
Weekly Estimated Net Usage Statistics.
주의하겠습니다
Gotcha!
앞으론 거시기에
폐가 가지 않게 할게요
Won't happen again. I wouldn't want
to do anything to hurt your WENUS.
나 같으면 일 못하는 사람
가만 안 둬
I'll take "ldiots in the Workplace"
for 200, Alex.
깜찍한 정도가 아니거든
It's not just that she's cute, okay?
It's just that...
콱 깨물어주고 싶어
...she's really, really cute.
괜찮아, 회사에
목매달 필요 없어
It doesn't matter. You don't dip
your pen in the company ink.
이해해, 나도
일 정말 못하잖아
God, I even know that
and I'm pretty much unemployable.
Ross, your little creature's got
the remote again.
오빠, 원숭이가
또 리모콘 만져
Marcel, give Rossy the remote.
마르셀!
리모콘 이리 줘야지
꼭 진짜 같아요
Marcel!
마르셀
Marcel, you give Rossy
the remote right now!
리모콘 당장 못 줘!
내가 이기면
집에 가야 된다
You give Rossy the remote
빨리 내놔
- 죽인다
- 내가 고칠게
-Great.
-Relax. I'll fix it.
세상에! 쟨 스페인어
할 때도 따발총이네
Oh, cool!
Urkel in Spanish is Urkel.
뭘 어쩐 거야?
How did he do this?
1년 내내 크리스마스 기분
내라고 전구를 안 뗀 거야?
Is leaving Christmas lights up your
plan to keep us merry all year long?
새해 밝으면 떼겠다던
사람이 깜빡 잊은 모양이야
No, someone was supposed to take them
down but obviously someone forgot.
Someone was supposed to write,
"Rach, take down the lights"...
'레이첼, 전구 떼'라고
쪽지 남겨야 할 사람이 잊은...
...and put it on the refrigera
-How long has that been there?
-A really long time.
언제부터 여기 있었어?
-Where you been?
-Riff's.
어디 갔다 와?
리프에 다시 갔지
우르술라가 날 좋아하나봐
I think Ursula likes me.
I ordered coffee.
커피 시켰는데 참치 샌드위치랑
감자 튀김까지 가져왔어
She brought me a tuna melt
and four plates of curly fries.
Score.
대단한걸!
She is so hot!
화끈한 여자야
근데 진도 나가기 전에
물어라도 보는 게...
Before you do anything Joey-like,
you might want to run it by....
- 그럴까?
- 그래
-Pheebs?
-Yeah.
- 피비?
- 응?
Is it okay
if I asked out your sister?
너희 언니랑 데이트해도
괜찮겠어?
Why? Why would you want
to do that? Why?
왜? 꼭 그래야만
하는 거야?
So if we went out on a date,
she'd be there.
맘에 드는 여자가
바로 네 언니니까
Well, I'm not my sister's,
you know, whatever.
난 언니가 아냐
알잖아?
한 땐 같은 알에
들어있었지만
And I mean, it's true,
we were one egg once.
But you know,
we've grown apart so....
떨어져 나왔는걸
- 왜 안 되겠어? 만나
- 고마워
I don't know. Why not?
Cool. Thanks.
-You okay?
-Yeah, I'm fine.
- 괜찮은 거야?
- 물론이지
Do you wanna watch
Laverne y Shirley?
스페인어로 나오는
연속극 볼래?
죄송해요
Sorry.
Hi. Sorry I'm late.
Where's Carol?
- 안녕!
늦어서 미안해
캐롤은?
학부모 면담한다고
학교에 있어
Stuck at school.
Some parent-teacher thing.
You can go.
I'll get the information.
- 내가 배울 테니 가도 돼
- 아냐
아냐, 우리 둘 다
배우는 게 좋잖아?
No, I think I should stay.
We should both know what's going on.
그래, 퍽도 재밌겠다
Oh, good. This will be fun.
We're gonna start with some basic
third-stage breathing exercises.
기초 세 번째 단계
호흡법을 배워보겠어요
엄마들은 기대주시고
Moms, get on your back.
코치 분들은 엄마 머리를
받쳐주세요
And coaches, you should
be supporting Mommy's head.
-What?
- 뭐?
- 뭐야?
나더러 엄마를 하라고?
-I'm supposed to be the mommy?
-I'll play my sperm card once more.
난 정자도 나오는 몸이라구
I have to miss the coaching training
because I'm a woman?
여자란 이유로 코치 수업을
놓치란 말야?
- 그럼 어떻게 할까?
- 동전 던지기로 해
-So, what do we do?
-I'll flip you for it.
동전 던지기? 싫어
난 앞면!
Flip me for it? No, no.
Heads!
뒷면이야, 엄마
On your back, Mom!
엄마들, 숨을 깊이
몰아쉬세요
All right, mommies, take a nice
deep, cleansing breath.
Good.
좋아요
이제 여러분의 질이
활짝 열리는 상상을 하세요
Now imagine your vagina is opening
like a flower.
- 더글라스 씨, 안녕하세요?
- 별로야
-Mr. D! How's it going, sir?
-It's been better.
The Annual Net Usage
Statistics are in.
- 연간 전산망사용 통계가 말야
- 네?
-And?
-It's pretty ugly.
엉망이야
70년대 이후 최악이지
We haven't seen an ANUS
this bad since the '70s.
그래서요?
-What does this mean?
-We'll be laying off people.
부마다 한 명씩
감원해야겠네
I know I was late last week.
But I slept funny and
지난주에 지각한 건 잠을
이상하게 자서 머리가...
자넨 아냐
앉게
Not you. Relax.
Ever have to fire anyone?
자를 사람 있나?
없지만 걱정 마세요
저도 이름 값은 한다구요
No, but that's not a problem.
That's why my name's on the door.
Do you know when I'm getting
my name on the door?
문에 언제부터 이름 달았게요?
I don't know.
I put it in the thing.
몰라, 유심히 안 봤는데
It's okay.
So, who is it gonna be?
괜찮습니다
누가 좋을까요?
니나!
Nina!
니나...
Nina.
니나!
니나...
괜찮으세요?
Are you okay?
그럼, 물론이지
Yes. Yes, I am.
Listen, the reason that
I called you in here today was....
이렇게 오라고 한 건...
Please don't hate me.
날 원망하진 마
뭐죠?
What?
Would you like
to have dinner sometime?
언제 저녁이나 먹을까?
So, what do you want
for your birthday?
피비, 생일 날
뭐 해줄까?
What I want is for my mom
to be alive and enjoy it with me.
엄마가 살아 계셔서
같이 보내면 좋겠어
그럼...
Okay. Let me put it this way.
Anything from Crabtree & Evelyn?
화장품 가게에
있는 것 중에 골라
-Bath salts would be nice!
-Okay! Good.
- 목욕소금!
- 알았어
What is this place?
여기 왜 왔더라?
You're cold, I have to pee and
there's coffee. How bad could it be?
넌 춥고 난 쉬 마려운데
카페가 보이길래 들어왔겠지
이유를 알 것 같아
I think we have an answer.
Why is she here?
여기서 뭐하는 거지?
This could be God's way
of telling us to eat at home.
집에 가서 밥 먹으라는
신의 계시야
리프에서 짤린 걸까?
-Think Riff's fired her?
-No, we were there last night.
아니, 어젯밤에도 계속
황새치만 가져오던걸
Are you gonna go to the...?
화장실 가게?
주문하고 나서 갈래
그 여자 맞지?
-I'll wait till we order. It's her.
-lt looks like her.
생긴 건 딱이네
-Excuse me?
-Yeah.
- 실례할게요
- 네?
Hi, it's us!
안녕하세요?
우리예요
Right. And it's me!
네, 저예요
-So you're here too?
-As much as you are.
여기에도 계시네요
피차일반이죠
Your turn.
네 차례야
- 뭐 먹을지 정했어요
- 잘 됐네요
-We know what we want.
-That's good.
-Two caffe lattes.
-And some biscotti.
- 카페라떼 두 잔이면 돼요
- 과자 조금 하구요
Good choice.
잘 생각하셨어요
- 틀림없어
- 그래
-It's definitely her.
-Yeah.
I can't believe you haven't told
that girl she doesn't have a job.
그 여자 잘렸단 얘길
아직도 못했단 말야?
You haven't taken down
the Christmas lights.
크리스마스 전구
아직도 안 뗐어?
Congratulations! You've found
the world's thinnest argument.
유치하게 대꾸해줘서 고마워
I'm finding the right moment.
때를 봐서 얘기할 거야
데이트 중이니까 쉽겠네
That shouldn't be so hard
now that you're dating.
'자긴 잘렸어, 난 출근해야
되니까 후딱 해버리자'
"Honey, you're fired. But how
about a quickie before I go to work?"
- 안녕
- 왔어?
Once you're inside,
you don't have to knock anymore.
들어왔으면
노크할 필요 없어
내가 나갈게
I'll get it.
-Hi, Mr. Heckles.
-You're doing it again.
헤클스 씨 아니세요?
또 시작이군
아무 짓도 안 했는데요
앉아서 얘기만 했다구요
We're not doing anything.
We're sitting and talking quietly.
조용히요
천장으로 다 들린다구
I can hear you through the ceiling.
고양이가 잠을 설쳐
My cats can't sleep.
- 고양이도 없잖아요?
- 곧 생길 거야
-You don't even have cats.
-I could have cats.
안녕히 가세요
-Goodbye, Mr. Heckles.
-We'll try to keep it down.
앞으론 조심할게요
피비, 부탁이 있어
Phoebe, do me a favor. Try this on.
I want to make sure it fits.
이거 맞나 입어봐
벌써 선물 주는 거야?
정말 예쁘...
My first birthday present!
This is really
아냐, 우르술라 줄 거야
잘 맞나 보려구
No, no, it's for Ursula.
I just figured size-wise....
Sure. Yeah. Okay, it fits.
그랬구나
꼭 맞아
- 오늘도 만날 거야?
- 응, 아이스 쇼 보러 가
-Are you seeing her again?
-Yep, lce Capades.
This is serious. I've never known you
to pay for any kind of "capade."
네가 그런 데
돈을 쓰다니 놀랍다
I don't know. I like her.
그냥 우르술라가 좋아
뭔가 다르다구
She's different.
There's something about her
특별하다고나...
좋단 말이잖아
알았다구
That you like.
We get it. You like her. Great!
Phoebe, I asked you.
You said it was okay.
만나도 괜찮다면서?
근데 지금은 안 괜찮아
Maybe now it's not okay.
Okay. Maybe now I'm not okay
with it not being okay.
네가 안 괜찮다는 게
안 괜찮아
괜찮아
Okay!
계속 짜!
얼른!
IKnit, good woman, knit!
And that's the Chrysler Building
right there.
저게 크라이슬러 빌딩이야
-Nina!
-Mr. Douglas. Cool tie.
니나!
더글라스 씨
넥타이 멋진데요
She's still here.
아직 여기 있군
Yes. Yes, she is.
Didn't I memo you on this?
네, 그래요
말씀드렸던가요?
After I let her go, I got a call
from her psychiatrist, Dr. Flennan
해고 후 니나의 정신과의사
전화를 받았어요
Dr. Flennan
Dr. Flynn.
플레낸...
플린 박사란 사람인데
And he informed me that
she took the news rather badly.
의사 말이 충격 때문에
니나가 정상이 아니래요
In fact, he mentioned
the word "frenzy."
설마!
아까 보니...
-You're kidding! She seems so
-No. Nina? She's
니나가요?
정신이 오락가락 한다구요
If you asked her now...
지금은 해고당했다는 것도
기억 못 할걸요?
...she'd have no recollection
of being fired at all.
-That's unbelievable.
-And yet believable.
- 안 믿어져
- 믿으셔야죠
So I decided not to fire her again
until she'll be no threat to anyone.
모두가 안전하려면 당분간
해고 얘긴 안 하는 게 좋겠어요
I guess you never know what's
going on inside a person's head.
알겠네, 정말 사람 속은
알 수가 없단 말야
Well, I guess that's why
they call it psychology, sir.
심리학이 폼으로
있는 건 아니겠죠
잊혀지지 않는 소리죠
The sound Mom and Dad
will never forget.
이것이 바로
탄생의 신비입니다
For this, after all,
is the miracle of birth.
불 좀 켜주세요
출산이란 이런 거예요
Lights, please.
And that's having a baby.
다음주는 마지막 수업입니다
Next week is our final class.
수잔, 받아!
Susan, go deep.
- 난 못하겠어
- 왜 그래?
-It's just impossible.
-What is, honey?
What that woman did.
아까 그 여자 봤지?
I am not doing that.
It'll just have to stay in.
난 절대 못해
아기 안 낳을래
계속 갖고 있을 거야
Everything will be the same.
It'll just stay in.
-Carol, honey, it'll be all right.
-What do you know?
캐롤, 편안하게 생각해
당신이 뭘 알아?
당신 콧구멍에 고기 덩어리를
쑤셔 넣는대도 그런 말 나올까?
No one's asking you, "Mind if we push
this pot roast through your nostril?"
캐롤, 숨을 깊이 들이쉬어
Carol, sweetie. Cleansing breath.
겁이야 나겠지만
이렇게 생각해봐
I know it's frightening.
But big picture:
몇 시간은 고생스럽겠지만
The birth part is just one day.
When it's over, we'll all be
parents for the rest of our lives.
그것만 견디면 우린 평생을
부모로 사는 거야
그만큼 가치 있는 일이야
맞지, 로스?
I mean, that's what this is
all about, right? Ross?
Ross?
로스!
I'm gonna be a father.
난 아빠가 돼
-This is news to you?
-I knew I was having a baby.
걱정돼서 그래?
가만히 있으면 저절로 아빠가
되는 줄 알았는데 아니겠더라구
I just never realized
the baby was having me.
-You'll be great.
-How can you say that?
잘 해낼 거야
난 마르셀이 욕실 깔개
물어뜯는 것도 단속 못해
I can't even get Marcel
to stop eating the bathmat.
-How will I raise a kid?
-Some scientists are now saying...
아이를 어떻게 키우겠냐구?
원숭이랑 아이랑은 다르다고
주장하는 과학자도 있어
...that monkeys and babies
are actually different.
You might want to look into it.
직접 조사해보든지
-Where you going?
-Out.
- 어디 가?
- 데이트
With...?
누구랑?
알잖아
Yes.
Can I just ask you one question?
하나만 묻자
Have you two, you know,
like, you know?
둘이... 있잖아
있잖아...
You know, yet?
있잖아?
아직이야?
네가 상관할 일은 아니지만
아직이야, 됐어?
Not that it's any of your business,
but no, we haven't.
You meant sex, right?
섹스 얘기였지?
- 시간 되세요?
- 물론, 왜 그래?
-Do you have a sec?
-Sure. What's up?
The past few days, people have been
avoiding me and giving me weird looks.
요 며칠 사람들이 자꾸
절 피하고 이상한 눈으로 봐요
Well, maybe that's because
they're jealous of us.
그건 아마...
- 우릴 샘내는 걸 거야
- 그렇다 치고
Maybe. But that doesn't explain
why they keep taking my scissors.
근데 가위는
왜 자꾸 뺏어갈까요?
Maybe that's because
you're getting a big raise!
니나 봉급이 엄청
뛰어서일 거야
- 정말요?
- 왜 아니겠어?
-I am?
-Sure. Why not?
세상에!
멋지세요
Oh, my God! You're amazing!
You don't know.
모르는 소리!
Helen, do the paperwork
on Miss Bookbinder's raise.
헬렌, 니나 봉급 인상 건
처리됐지?
You still want me to send her
psychological profile to Personnel?
니나의 정신과 기록을
인사과에 넘기라구요?
뭐요?
Helen drinks.
헬렌이 취했어
Will you marry me?
우리 결혼할까?
청혼하고 나서
거의 들켜버렸어
So after the proposal,
I kind of unraveled.
Right. Because you were really
in control up until then.
그 전까진 정말
완벽했는데 말야
-I told her everything.
-How'd she take it?
- 결국 다 털어놨지 뭐
- 그랬더니 뭐래?
가볍게
호치키스로 찍더군
Pretty well.
Except for the stapler thing.
교훈 하나!
A tip. If you're ever
in a similar situation...
그런 상황에선 절대
책상에 손 올려놓지 마
... never, ever leave your hand
on the desk.
이제 알아냈어
Okay, I think I get how to do this.
Can we turn it off? Make them
go away because I can't watch.
미안하지만 꺼줄래?
TV 볼 기분이 아냐
Okay, they're gone.
- 껐어
- 그래
Are you all right?
너 괜찮아?
응, 그냥 우르술라 때문에...
It's just this whole
stupid Ursula thing.
근데 말야, 조이가 우르술라랑
데이트하는 게 그렇게 싫어?
Pheebs, can I ask? So he's going out
with her. Is it really so terrible?
Yeah.
그래
언니가 못 됐다거나
그런 뜻은 아냐
I'm not saying she's evil or anything.
늘 내 걸 깨뜨린단 거지
She's just always breaking my stuff.
When I was 8, she threw my Judy Jetson
Thermos under the bus.
8살 땐 내 보온병을
버스에 던져 깨뜨렸어
And then when I was 1 2,
she broke my collarbone.
12살 땐 내 쇄골을
부러뜨렸어
She didn't mean to do it
but I think it still counts.
물론 실수로 그랬지만
아직도 열 받아
또 랜디 브라운이란
애가 있었는데...
And then there's Randy Brown,
who was like
친한 친구랑 똑같이 생긴
남자 사귀어 봤어?
Have you ever had a boyfriend
who was your best friend?
아니
랜디가 그랬다니까
언니가 내 친구를 뺏은 거야
That's what he was for me.
And she kind of stole him away
and then broke his heart.
그러다 언니한테 채이고는
Then he wouldn't talk to me anymore.
나랑은 말도 안 했어
He didn't want to be around anything
that looked like either one of us.
우리랑 비슷한 건 뭐든
꼴도 보기 싫다고 했대
세상에...
I know Joey's not my boyfriend
or my thermos...
조이가 내 애인도 아니고
내 보온병도 아니지만
...or anything, but
- 그래도 난...
- 그런 일 없을 거야
-You won't lose him.
-You gotta talk to Joey.
조이랑 얘기해봐
그럴게
그래, 이런 사연을 알면
조이도...
-lf he knew how you felt
-But he's falling in love with her.
눈에 콩깍지가 씌었는걸
겨우 1주일 만났어
아직 잠도 같이 안 잤다구
They've been going out a week.
They haven't even slept together yet.
That's not serious.
별 사이 아냐
그래
Okay. Okay.
알았어
무슨 일이야?
May we help you?
What are you doing?
It's freezing! Come inside.
레이첼, 추운데 뭐해?
얼른 들어와
아냐, 이거 떼라며?
No, you wanted me to take them down...
그래서 떼고 있잖아
...so I'm taking them down, okay?
레이첼!
Rachel!
난 괜찮아
I'm okay. I'm okay.
헤클스 씨!
Mr. Heckles?
Mr. Heckles, could you
help me, please?
좀 도와주실래요?
This is just the kind of thing
I was talking about.
내가 말한 게
바로 이런 거였어
My friend was taking down
Christmas lights...
크리스마스 전구 떼다가
발코니에서 떨어졌는데
...and may have broken her ankle.
발목이 부러졌을지도 몰라요
My God, you still have
your Christmas lights up?
크리스마스 전구를
여태 달아놨어요?
작성해서 가지고 오세요
-Fill this out and bring it back.
-Here you go.
All right. Name, address.
좋아
이름... 주소...
지금 사용중인 약은?
-Are you currently on any medication?
-No.
없어...
있다! 입술 연고
Oh, wait! Yes. Blistex.
-No. In case of emergency, call...?
-You.
그건 아냐
긴급히 연락할 사람?
너!
- 정말?
- 그래
-Really?
-Yeah.
Oh, that is so sweet!
너무 고마워
세상에!
나도 사랑해
Gosh, love you. Okay, insurance?
의료보험?
Oh, yeah, check it.
Definitely gonna want some of that!
체크해
하나 들어야할 텐데
-You don't have insurance?
-How much will this cost?
의료보험 없어?
왜? 얼마나 나오길래?
엑스레이만 해도
몇 백 달러 줘야될걸?
X-rays alone could be $200!
- 그럼 어쩌지?
- 별 다른 방법은 없어
-What are we gonna do?
-There's not much we can do.
네 걸 쓰면 어때?
Unless I use yours.
-No, no, no.
-Now wait a second.
그건 안 되지
'긴급히 연락할 사람'이
누구라고 했더라?
Who did I just put
as my emergency person?
That's insurance fraud.
그건 보험 사기야
All right then, forget it.
Might as well just go home.
알았어, 됐어
그냥 집에 갈래
알았어
이리 와
-Okay, come here. I hate this.
-Thank you. I love you.
- 못 살아!
- 고마워, 사랑해
저기요
Hi. I'm gonna need
a new set of these forms.
새로 한 부 주시겠어요?
-Why?
-I am really an idiot.
왜죠?
나도 바보지!
친구 거 대신 써준다는 게
그만 제 이름을 썼지 뭐예요?
I was filling out her form...
...and instead of putting
her information I put mine.
정말 바보군요
You are an idiot.
Yep, that's me. I am that stupid.
그렇죠?
아주 돌머리예요
I had a dream. I was playing
football with my kid.
어제 꿈에 우리 아기랑
풋볼을 했어
- 멋진데
- 좋았겠다
-That's nice.
-No, no. With him.
걜 갖고 했다고!
I'm on this field,
and they hike me the baby.
경기장에 섰는데
아기를 패스 받았어
'탬파베이' 수비가 달려들어서
가만있을 수만은 없었지
I've gotta do something. The Tampa Bay
defense is coming right at me!
'탬파베이'는
실력 꽝이야
-Tampa Bay's got a terrible team.
-Right, but...
맞아, 하지만...
...it is just me and the baby,
so I'm thinking they can take us.
설마 나랑 아기도
못 당할라구?
그래서 필드로
냅다 던져버렸지
And so I just heave it downfield!
너 미친 거 아냐?
-What are you, crazy? That's a baby!
-He should take the sack?
그럼 매트라도 깔까?
Anyway, suddenly I'm downfield.
갑자기 난 필드에 가있고
And I realize I'm the one
who's supposed to catch him.
그 애를 내가
받아야 하더라구
I know I'm not gonna
get there in time.
빼도 박도 못하는 상황이니
그냥 뛰었어, 계속 뛰었지
So I am running and running.
That is when I woke up.
그러다 깨버렸어
무슨 놈의 아빠가
그러냐구?
See? I am so not ready
to be a father.
너무 걱정 마
You're gonna be fine.
You're one of the most caring,
responsible men in North America.
넌 북미에서 제일 세심하고
책임감 강한 남자야
훌륭한 아빠가 될 거라구
You're gonna make a great dad.
그래, 블로킹만
좀 보강하면 돼
Yeah, you and the baby
just need better blocking.
Have you ever been to
the Rainbow Room? Is it expensive?
너희 '레인보우 룸' 가봤어?
되게 비싸지?
주문만 안 하면 돼
Well, only if you order stuff.
우르술라와 가려구
생일이거든
I'm taking Ursula tonight.
It's her birthday.
피비 생일은 어쩌고?
-What about Phoebe's birthday?
-When's that?
언젠데?
-Tonight.
-What are the odds of that happening?
오늘밤
하필 왜 같은 날이지?
You take your time.
잘 생각해봐
이제 감 잡았군
There it is!
-What'll you do?
-What can I do?
어쩔 거야?
어쩌긴? 우르술라를
섭섭하게 할 순 없어
I don't wanna screw it up with Ursula.
그럼 네 친구 피비는?
And your friend?
If she's my friend, she'll understand.
Wouldn't you?
진짜 친구라면 이해할 거야
너흰 안 그래?
If you tried that on my birthday...
내 생일날 그랬다간
그 날이 바로 네 제삿날이다
...you'd be staring at
the end of a hissy fit.
사프란만 약간
투약하면 될 거야
Saffron makes all the difference.
- 모니카 양?
- 네?
-Okay. Monica?
-Yes.
-Yes, she is.
-Hi, this is my friend Rachel.
얘예요
안녕하세요?
얜 친구 레이첼이에요
닥터 미첼입니다
-Hi, I'm Dr. Mitchell.
-And I'm Dr. Rosen.
전 친구 닥터 로즌이구요
I'm okay here.
- 내가 들지
- 괜찮아, 이리 줘
Actually, that's all right.
You can take your break.
가서 좀 쉬어
No, this is why I became a doctor.
Ankles and stuff like that.
내가 왜 의사가 됐는데?
발목 전문이죠
-Aren't you too cute to be a doctor?
-Excuse me?
- 의사치곤 너무 섹시해요
- 뭐라구요?
God, young, young. I meant young.
Young to be a doctor. Good, Rach.
그게 아니라 젊다구요
의사치곤 너무 젊으세요
- 잘 한다, 레이첼
- 고마워
-Thank you.
-Right.
뭘...
좀 삔 것 뿐이랬어
별 거 아냐
He said it was just a sprain.
-You left out the stupid part.
-It's not stupid.
바보짓은 왜 빼?
바보짓은? 너무너무 섹시한
의사들의 데이트 신청 하길래
The cute doctors asked us out
for tomorrow, and I said yes.
응한 거라구
I think it's insane.
They work for the hospital.
완전히 미친 짓이야
범행현장에 제 발로
들어가는 꼴이라구
It's like returning
to the scene of the crime.
- 데이트 취소하자
- 뭐?
-I say we blow off the dates.
-What? They are cute.
섹시하다구, 게다가 의사야
섹시한 의사, 의사인데 섹시해
They are doctors. Cute doctors.
Doctors who are cute.
All right, what have
we learned so far?
배운 거 복습해볼까요?
Oh, God. Okay.
- 왔다!
- 어쩌지
Surprise!
놀랐지?
What are you doing?
You scared the crap out of me!
애 떨어질 뻔했잖아
-Was that the cake?
-Yeah. I got a lemon schmoosh.
- 케이크야?
- 그래
레몬 묵사발이지
Come on. She'll be here any minute.
피비가 금방 올 거야
Hope it's okay.
괜찮아야 될 텐데
"Happy Birthday Peehee."
생일 축하해, '피미'
Maybe we can make a "B" out of a rose.
장미로 'ㅂ'자
만들면 되겠는데
그 장미 아주
쓸 만 하군 그래
We'll just use
our special cake tools.
다들 뭐 해?
-What's going on?
-We just
놀랐지!
Surprise!
너무 좋다!
This is so great! Oh, my God!
This was not at all scary.
하나도 안 놀랜 거 있지
'생일 축하해, 피미'
Look! "Happy Birthday Peehee."
특이한 별명이다
맘에 들어!
What a strange new nickname.
I like it! Oh, my God!
Hi, everybody. Hi, Betty! Betty, hi!
모두 안녕?
안녕, 베티?
용케도 찾았네
You found Betty!
Oh, my gosh! This is so great.
너무 기뻐
한 자리에 모이니까
정말 좋아
Everybody I love is in the same room.
Where's Joey?
조이는 어딨어?
Did you see Betty?
베티도 왔다!
이 말린 토마토 사업도
꽤 할 만할 것 같단 말야
I wouldn't mind having a piece
of this sun-dried tomato business.
Five years ago, if somebody had said,
"A tomato that's like a prune"...
5년 전만 해도 누가 이런
쭈그러진 우거지상 들이밀면
'당장 꺼져! ' 했을 테지만
... I'd have said, "Get out!"
Dad, before I was born,
did you freak out?
저 태어나기 전에
아버지도 불안하셨어요?
불안하긴! 난 그냥 누가
나한테 말린 토마토를...
I'm not freaking out! I'm saying,
if someone had come to me
아버지!
제 아기 말이에요
Dad, I'm talking about
the whole baby thing.
혼란스럽지 않으셨어요?
Did you ever get this sort of...
... panicky, "Oh, my God,
I'm gonna be a father" thing?
'아! 내가 아빠가 되다니! '
하면서 말이에요
No. We just had kids back then.
아니!
애를 갖기만 했지
그런 생각은 안 했어
We didn't think about it.
What else could the sun dry, I wonder?
말릴 수 있는 게
또 뭐가 있을까?
Dad, come on. IKids.
아버지, 아기 말예요
Look, your mother really did the work.
I was busy with the business.
알았다
네 엄마가 고생했지
난 일 땜에 바빴거든
I wasn't around that much.
Is that what this is about?
신경을 못 썼단다
이제 와서 따지자는 거냐?
그냥 궁금했던 거예요
No, I was just wondering.
시간이 너무 없었어
지금도 안 늦었다
We can make up for that.
We can do stuff together.
You always wanted to go to Colonial
Williamsburg. Let's do that.
'윌리엄스버그' 박물관 가자고
노랠 불러댔지, 가볼래?
말씀만이라도 고마워요
제가 궁금한 건...
Thanks, Dad, really.
You know, I just....
아빠가 됐구나 실감하신 게
언제예요?
I just needed to know...
...when did you start
to feel like a father?
그건 아마...
Well, I guess it must've been
the day after you were born.
네가 태어난
다음 날일 거야
We were in the hospital room,
your mom was asleep...
간호사들이 아기를 안고 병실로
오더니 널 나한테 넘겨주는 거야
...and they brought you in
and gave you to me.
You were this ugly little red thing.
시뻘건 게 정말 못났었지
근데 갑자기 네가 그 작은
손으로 내 손가락을 잡았어
All of a sudden you grabbed
my finger with your fist...
아주 꽉...
움켜쥐었지
...and you squeezed it so tight.
그 때 깨달았단다
And that's when I knew.
So you don't wanna go
to Williamsburg?
'윌리엄스버그' 안 갈래?
We can go to Williamsburg.
못 갈 것도 없죠
Eat your fish.
생선 먹어라
-Rachel, the cute doctors are here!
-Okay, coming.
레이첼!
섹시한 의사들 왔어
응, 나가
-Hi, come on in.
-Hi, Jeffrey.
- 오셨어요?
- 안녕하세요?
들어오세요
안녕하세요?
We brought wine.
와인 가져왔어요
'어네스트와 토바 보그나인'
Look. It's from the cellars
of Ernest and Tova Borgnine.
맘에 들어요?
-How could we resist?
-That's great!
좋아요!
너도 좀 봐
-Monica, how's the ankle?
-It's....
- 모니카, 발목은 어때요?
- 뭐 그냥...
Why don't you tell them?
After all, it is your ankle.
어서 말씀드리렴
네 발목이잖니?
It's feeling a lot better.
Thank you.
많이 좋아졌어요
고마워요
Why don't you guys sit down,
and we'll get you some glasses?
좀 앉아 계세요
잔 가지고 갈게요
그러죠
그래요
Okay. Stat!
후딱!
Why don't we just tell them
who we really are? It'll be fine.
그냥 솔직히
불어버리는 게 어때?
아무래도 그러는 게
좋을 것 같아
-We'll get in trouble.
-Would you stop being such a wuss?
그러다 큰일나게?
계속 깝깝하게 굴래?
A wuss? Excuse me
for living in the real world.
깝깝?
제발 정신 좀 차릴래?
-So?
-So they still seem normal.
어때?
- 아직까진 정상으로 보여
- 진짜 정상이니까
Because they are.
여태껏 병원에서 만나
데이트한 여자들 중...
When we go out with women
from the hospital
Relax. Take a look around.
There are no pagan altars.
한번 둘러보라구
이교도 제단도 없고
No piles of bones in the corners.
They're fine. Go like this:
구석에 뼈다귀 더미도 없잖아
멀쩡하다니까
이렇게 해봐
We're not going to do it.
Sometimes you can be such a baby!
데이트하지 말자 그랬지?
넌 정말 애 같아
누가 애야?
-I am not a baby.
-Be serious. Every time
- 다 네가 깐깐한 탓이야
- 넌 네가 공주인 줄 알지?
-You act like a princess.
-You know what?
- 너 그거 알아?
- 뭐?
- 아냐고?
- 뭘?
Every day you are becoming more
and more like your mother. Excuse me.
넌 하루하루
너희 엄마 닮아가
자! 갑니다!
Here we go.
고마워요
Great place.
How long have you lived here?
집이 참 좋네요
얼마나 사셨어요?
고마워요
전 6년쯤 됐고
I've been here about six years.
레이첼은 몇 달 전에
이사왔어요
And Rachel moved in a few months ago.
전 결혼할 뻔했다가...
See, I was supposed to get married,
but I left the guy at the altar.
식장에서 도망쳤거든요
- 정말요?
- 네
-Really?
-Yeah.
너무 이기적인 짓이었지만
Yeah, I know it's pretty selfish,
but hey, that's me!
제가 원래 그래요
-Try the hummus.
-Monica, what do you do?
훔무스 좀 드세요
모니카, 직업이 뭐예요?
I am a chef at a restaurant uptown.
작은 식당 주방장이에요
- 좋네요
- 그렇죠 뭐
-Good for you.
-Yeah, it is.
Mostly because I get to boss people
around, which I just love to do.
남들 부려먹을 수 있다는 게
제일 맘에 들어요
-This hummus is great.
-God bless the chickpea.
훔무스 맛있네요
가엾은 병아리콩!
Oh, God! I am so spoiled!
이런!
전 싸가지가 없어요
That's it.
그렇다구요
전 도벽이 있죠
I shoplift.
립스틱이 주머니에 들어있는지
모르고 그랬던 거잖아?
You had no idea that lipstick
was in your pocket.
전 주제도 모르고
제가 예쁜 줄 안답니다
Did I tell you that I think
I'm so much cuter than I am?
제가 고등학교 때
얘기했던가요?
And have I mentioned that back
in high school I was a cow?
전 뚱녀였어요
전 오줌도 쌌죠
I used to wet my bed.
I use my breasts
to get people's attention.
전 가슴으로
사람들 관심을 끌어요
We both do that!
피차 마찬가지야
모니카와 레이첼의 집입니다
Monica and Rachel's apartment.
네, 잠깐만요
레이첼, 아버지세요
Just one second.
Rachel, it's your dad.
Hi, Dad. No, no, it's me.
아빠!
아뇨, 저예요
아빠, 지금은 말하기
좀 곤란해요
Listen, Dad, I can't talk right now.
한 가지 꼭 말씀드릴 게
있어요
But there's something....
There's something
I've been meaning to tell you.
잠깐 실례할게요
-Excuse me.
-Remember back in freshman year?
저 신입생 때
기억나세요?
빌리 드레스덴랑
아빠 침대에서 잤어요
Well, Billy Dreskin
and I had sex on your bed.
아빠!
Daddy.
아빠, 제가 왜 빌리랑
잤겠어요?
Why? Why would I sleep
with Billy Dreskin?
His father tried to put you
out of business! You are dead!
걔네 아빠랑
아빠랑 앙숙인데요
죽었어!
레이첼, 콘돔 네 거니?
Hey, Rachel? Are these your condoms?
아뇨, 모니카예요
또 술 펐어요
Oh, no, that was just Monica.
She's drunk again.
피비, '안바삭'은
단어 아냐
I don't think "scrunchy" is a word.
바삭'도 되는데
'안바삭'이 왜?
Why not, if "crunchy" is a word?
그럼 '안인대'도 되게?
Then I'm using that same argument
for "fligament."
쟤 또 리모콘 만져
-Ross, he's got the remote again.
-Good.
잘됐네, 똑바로
돌려놓을지도 모르잖아
Maybe he can switch it back.
Maybe not.
아닌가보네
아빠, 딴 전화 왔거든요
Okay, Daddy? That's the other line.
제 침대에서도 아니에요
Okay, no, not even in my bedroom.
네, 끊을게요
Okay. Okay. Bye-bye.
여보세요?
Hello?
네
Hold on a second. Let me check
and see if she's here.
잠깐 기다리세요
집에 있나 확인하구요
병원의 그 접수처 여자야
It's the woman from the hospital.
There's a problem.
접수신청서가 잘못됐대
어떡해?
-What do we do?
-Just find out what they want.
이걸 어떡하지?
낸들 알아?
왜 그러는지 물어봐
그래, 네가 해
Okay. No, you do it.
제가 모니카인데요
Hello. This is Monica. Yeah?
네?
Oh, okay. Yes, we'll be right down.
Thank you.
네, 금방 갈게요
고맙습니다
뭐래?
서명을 안 한 게 있대
We forgot to sign one
of the admissions forms.
You were right. This was just
not worth it. Let me just change.
그래, 네 말이 맞아
정말 못해먹겠다
고마워
- 옷 갈아입고 올게
- 그래
-"Garge"?
-Nautical term.
- 해뵤?
- 항해 용어야
- 거짓말
- 알았어
-Cheating man.
-Okay.
- 안녕
- 아직 전화 안 와?
- 응
-She still didn't call?
-No.
왜 그래?
Trouble?
Your sister stood me up.
네 언니한테 바람맞았어
Don't you hate it
when people aren't there for you?
그걸 어째!
너 바람맞는 거 싫어하잖아?
-What is that?
-"Tushy."
그게 뭐야?
방뎅이
-Did you try calling her?
-For two days.
- 전화는 해봤어?
- 이틀 내내 했지
식당으로 하니까
바쁘다면서 안 바꿔줬어
At the restaurant
they said she was busy.
나한테 그러다니
안 믿어져
I can't believe she's blowing me off!
스페셜 샐러드
2인분 시켰는데요?
-We had the two chef salads.
-And how were they?
몇 인분 나왔길래요?
아직 안 나와서
목 빠지게 기다리고있어요
No, we haven't had them yet.
We're still hoping to have them.
알겠어요
Okay.
언니!
-You got a minute?
-Yeah, I'm just working.
잠깐 시간 돼?
일하는 중인데 뭐
- 있잖아...
- 응?
So.
-I got you a birthday present.
-Wow, you remembered.
생일선물 가져왔어
기억하고 있었구나!
-It's a Judy Jetson thermos.
-Like the kind you
주디 젯슨 보온병이네
- 맞아, 예전에...
- 그래
Right. Oh, I got
something for you too.
나도 줄 거 있어
-How'd you know I was coming?
-Yeah, twin thing.
내가 올 줄 어떻게 알고?
우린 쌍둥이잖니?
이거 꿈이야 생시야?
I can't believe you did this.
이거 정말...
꿈일 거야
So, what's the deal with you and Joey?
그나저나 조이랑은
어떻게 된 거야?
조이 정말 괜찮지
근데 끝났어
Oh, right. He is so great.
But that's over.
- 그 사람도 알아?
- 누구?
-Does he know?
-Who?
조이
Joey. You know,
he's really nutsy about you.
지금 언니한테
아주 미쳐있다구
-He is? Why?
-You got me.
그래? 왜?
- 그러게
- 정말!
Right. Excuse me, doesn't this
come with a side salad?
여기요!
샐러드는 안 갖다주세요?
So are you gonna call him?
전화할 거야?
쟤가 나 좋아하는 것 같아?
-You think he likes me?
-No. Joey.
조이 말야
Oh! No, he is so smart.
He'll figure it out.
아니, 알아서
눈치는 챌 거야
Do you want some chicken?
닭고기 좀 먹을래?
No. No food with a face.
얼굴 달린 건 안 먹잖아
-You have not changed.
-Yeah, you too.
여전하구나
언니도 그래
고마워
Thanks. Excuse me? My side salad?
이봐요! 샐러드는요?
Service here is horrible.
Now I know what people mean.
이 집 서비스가 엉망이라더니
정말이네
저희 기억하시죠?
Hi! Remember us?
좀 전에 신청서에 서명
필요하다고 전화하셨죠?
You called about needing
a signature on the form?
근데 통째로 다시 써야돼요
Well, it turns out we need a new one.
왜냐하면...
이름을 또 잘못 썼거든요
Because, you see,
I put the wrong name again.
-Because
-You're that stupid!
정말로 바보네요!
I am. I'm that stupid.
네, 정말 바보죠
And I'm gonna pay
for this with a check.
이건 수표로 계산할게요
Your insurance will cover that.
보험처리 되잖아요?
저도 별로 똘똘하진
못하거든요
I know. I'm just not
that bright either.
Mon, I'm sorry. I don't think
you're like your mother.
어젠 미안했어, 너 너희
엄마랑 하나도 안 똑같아
That's all right. And I don't
think you were selfish.
식장에서 뛰쳐나온 거
이기적인 거 아냐
Oh, and I'm sorry I said
you were a cow.
뚱녀라고 했던 것도 미안!
괜찮아, 뚱녀였는걸
That's okay, I was a cow.
맞아
I know. I'm just sorry I said it.
말해서 미안하다구
Worst case scenario:
Say you never feel like a father.
최악의 경우, 아버지란
사실을 못 느낀다고 쳐
아들하고 어떤 교감도
못 느낀다고 해봐
Say your son never feels
connected to you as one.
Say all of his relationships
are affected by this.
이게 그 애의 인간관계에
영향을 준다고 쳐
주제가 뭐야?
-Do you have a point?
-You know, you'd think I would.
그런 게 있을까?
What's up with the simian?
원숭이가 왜 저러지?
-It's just a fur ball.
-All right.
- 털이라도 삼켰나보지
- 그렇군
-Whose turn?
-Yours. I got 43 points for "kidney."
누구 차례지?
너! 'KIDNEY'로
43점 땄어
No, you got zero points for "idney."
아니, 'IDNEY'니까
빵점이야
'K' 있었어
'K'가 어디 갔지?
I had a "K." Where's my "K"?
You've got to help me!
My monkey swallowed a "K"!
제발 도와주세요
원숭이가 'K'를 삼켰어요
- 동물은 출입금지예요
- 모르시겠어요?
-Get that animal out!
-The animal hospital is across town.
그 먼 동물병원까지 가다간
숨넘어가요, 방법이 없다구요
무슨 일이야?
-What's going on?
-Marcel swallowed a Scrabble tile.
마르셀이 스크래블
타일을 삼켰어
Excuse me.
This hospital is for people!
미안하지만 여긴
사람 병원이에요
He is people! He has a name, okay?
얘도 사람이에요
이름도 있고 드라마도 본다구요
He watches Jeopardy!, he touches
himself when nobody's watching.
남이 안 볼 땐
자기 물건도 만져요
Please, have a heart.
너무 매정하시네요
- 제가 보죠
- 고마워요
-I'll take a look at him.
-Thanks.
미첼!
-Michael!
-Rachel.
- 레이첼?
- 네?
-What?
-Monica.
모니카!
- 안녕
안녕
Urs, what are you doing here?
I've been trying to call you.
우르술라! 어떻게 왔어?
전화를 얼마나 했다구
Listen....
있잖아...
'있잖아'란 말 하지마
나도 많이 해봐서 알아
Don't say "listen."
I know that "listen." I've said that.
-I'm sorry.
-I don't get it. What happened?
미안해
갑자기 왜 이래?
다리 아래서 한 말은 뭐야?
What about what
you said under the bridge?
Yeah. You should just forget about
what I said under the bridge.
그건...
그 때 한 말은 다 잊어
제 정신이 아니었다구
I was talking crazy that night.
I was so drunk.
너무 취했거든
술 안 마시잖아?
-You don't drink.
-That's right, I don't.
맞아, 안 마셔
-But I was drunk on you.
-Oh, Urs
그 땐 너한테 취했어
- 우르술라!
- 이젠 다 소용없어
But it's not gonna work.
왜?
내가 피비랑 친구라서?
Why? Is it because
I'm friends with Phoebe?
피비랑 안 만날 수 있어?
Would you stop hanging out with her?
아니, 안돼
그럴 순 없어
No, I couldn't do that.
그럼 피비 때문이야
Then yeah, it's because of Phoebe.
둘 중에 택해
So, you know, it's either her or me.
그럼...
미안하게 됐어
Then I'm sorry.
You know, you're gonna be
really hard to get over.
견뎌내기가 쉽지는
않을 거야
I know.
알아
I don't know whether it's just
because we're breaking up or what.
헤어지는 마당이라서
그런 건지 모르겠지만
오늘 최고로 예뻐 보여
-But you've never looked so beautiful.
-Really?
정말?
-Pheebs?
-Yeah.
- 피비?
- 응?
He looks so tiny.
얼굴이 반쪽이 됐어
- 방금 연락 받았어
- 괜찮아?
-We just heard.
-ls he okay?
의사가 'K'를 꺼냈어
The doctor got the "K" out.
'M'이랑 'O'도 나왔지
He also found an "M" and an "O."
We think he was trying
to spell out "monkey."
혹시 '몽키'를
쓰려던 게 아닐까?
별일 없을 거래
지금은 자는 거야
The doctor says he'll be fine.
He's just sleeping now.
이제 아빠 기분 나지?
-So, you feel like a dad yet?
-No. Why?
아니, 왜?
Come on, you came through.
You did what you had to do.
앞뒤 안 가리고 뛰면서
얘를 구했잖아
그게 아빠라니까
-That's very "dad."
-Look. He's waking up.
깼나봐
Hey, fella. How you doing?
좀 어때?